<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorials &amp; PPTs: C#, Unity 2D, Winforms, MVC, ASP, H046, H446...</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tutorials &amp; PPTs: C#, Unity 2D, Winforms, MVC, ASP, H046, H446...</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 11:22:36 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AS (year 1) - PowerPoints</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/alevel/year1/powerpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 11:22:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/alevel/year1/powerpoints/</guid>
      <description>Overview Below you will find links to the PowerPoints and associated resources that I use to deliver the OCR AS Level Computer Science Course.&#xA;H046/01 - Paper 1 Pseudocode Memory Programming (you will need some winforms experience for this one) RISC v CISC and Von Newmann v Harvard Evolution:- Please don&amp;rsquo;t worry about missing numbers, this has happened over time.&#xA;OS and CPU Scheduling Distributed, Embedded, Etc&amp;hellip; OS Compilers, Assemblers and Open Source Binary Arithmetic Floating Point and HEX Development Methodologies More evolution:- After changing textbooks I altered the order of the course, so some of the numbering goes a bit odd, lesson 12b has nothing to do with lesson 12 but they are delivered in that order.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 1 - Access an API with Winforms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/api/tutorial1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 11:22:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/api/tutorial1/</guid>
      <description>Overview: This tutorial will enable you to access data from an API in Winforms. The written guide (below) accompanies the video tutorial. It is a good place to start as you don&amp;rsquo;t need to learn MVC you can do everything you need within a familiar WinForms environment.&#xA;Video Tutorial It is accompanied by a video tutorial which you can view here:&#xA;Written Instructions Simply use the document below as a self-guided classroom / training room resource.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WinForms - Getting Started</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms1-gettingstarted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 10:50:33 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms1-gettingstarted/</guid>
      <description>Winforms - What is it? Winforms projects are a simple way to get started with C# programming. They combine a simple front end (screen) with a closely linked backend (code).&#xA;Below is a very short overview of how to build a simple winforms project using C#. For guidance with a bit more clarity follow this link to my winforms resources link here&#xA;How to work with Winforms (a short guide) You&amp;rsquo;ll need some free software, MS Visual Studio Community Edition, available here &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Download Visual Studio.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 1 - Make a character move!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/unity/unitymanual1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:42:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/unity/unitymanual1/</guid>
      <description>Overview - Player Setup: To use this guide you will need to download and install Unity and MS Visual Studio. It is recommended that you install the latest versions. Some of the screenshots in this guide have been taken from older versions but should not differ too much.&#xA;Simply use this guide as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A2 (second year) - Powerpoints</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/alevel/year2/powerpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 11:22:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/alevel/year2/powerpoints/</guid>
      <description>Overview Below you will find links to the PowerPoints and associated resources that I use to deliver the OCR A2 Level Computer Science Course.&#xA;Cheat Sheets Cheat Sheets&#xA;H446/01 - Paper 1 OOP for Projects Memory Von Newmann RISC v CISC GPU Processing Textbook Section 1 End OS and CPU Scheduling Compilers Assemblers Open Source Linkers and Loaders Binary Arithmetic Software Methodologies Sorting Algorithms Programming Paradigms Databases Assembly and LMC Cryptographic Hash Function HTML and CSS Search Engines Boolean Logic Networks Adders and Flip Flops Data Storage Final Bits of Paper 1 Laws and Ethics H446/02 - Paper 2 Abstraction and Decomposition Thinking Procedurally Problem Recognition Programming Fundamentals Pathfinding Revision Both Papers Revision - Checklist</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 2 - Car Data API in ASP/MVC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/api/tutorial2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 11:22:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/api/tutorial2/</guid>
      <description>Overview: This app requires you to create an account with: UK Vehicle Data, this can take up to two days to be authorised. Create your account as soon as you read this and come back to the tutorial once you have access.&#xA;Simply use the document below as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 1 - Choose a holiday!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms2-holidaytutorial-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:42:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms2-holidaytutorial-1/</guid>
      <description>Overview - Holiday Recommendation App: To use this guide you will need to download and install MS Visual Studio. It is recommended that you install the latest version. Some of the screenshots in this guide have been taken from older versions but should not differ too much.&#xA;Simply use this guide as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 2 - Making enemies!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/unity/unitymanual2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:10:23 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/unity/unitymanual2/</guid>
      <description>Overview- Enemies: To use this guide you will need to download and install Unity and MS Visual Studio. It is recommended that you install the latest versions. Some of the screenshots in this guide have been taken from older versions but should not differ too much.&#xA;Simply use this guide as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 3 - MVC with Spotify data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/api/tutorial3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 11:22:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/api/tutorial3/</guid>
      <description>Overview: This app requires you to create an account with: Spotify Developer. Create your account as soon as you read this and complete the tutorial once you have access.&#xA;Simply use the document below as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate. 1&#xA;CLICK HERE TO DOWNLOAD THE DOCUMENT&#xA;When editing any documents, please include an original author citation, thank you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 2...5 - coming soon!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms3-5tutorialfillerpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:42:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms3-5tutorialfillerpage/</guid>
      <description>Simply use this guide as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate. 1&#xA;When editing any documents, please include an original author citation, thank you.&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 3 - Spinning Saw Blades</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/unity/unitymanual3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:10:23 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/unity/unitymanual3/</guid>
      <description>Overview - Hazards: To use this guide you will need to download and install Unity and MS Visual Studio. It is recommended that you install the latest versions. Some of the screenshots in this guide have been taken from older versions but should not differ too much.&#xA;Simply use this guide as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 4 - Collectables and Basic UI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/unity/unitymanual4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:10:23 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/unity/unitymanual4/</guid>
      <description>Overview - Collectables: To use this guide you will need to download and install Unity and MS Visual Studio. It is recommended that you install the latest versions. Some of the screenshots in this guide have been taken from older versions but should not differ too much.&#xA;Simply use this guide as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 5 - Shooting - Ye ha!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/unity/unitymanual5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:10:23 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/unity/unitymanual5/</guid>
      <description>Overview - Shooting: To use this guide you will need to download and install Unity and MS Visual Studio. It is recommended that you install the latest versions. Some of the screenshots in this guide have been taken from older versions but should not differ too much.&#xA;Simply use this guide as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 6 - Object Orientation Part 1 of 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms6-oop1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:42:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms6-oop1/</guid>
      <description>Overview - Winforms and C# Object Orientation - The basics: To use this guide you will need to download and install MS Visual Studio. It is recommended that you install the latest version. Some of the screenshots in this guide have been taken from older versions but should not differ too much.&#xA;Simply use this guide as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 6 - Sounds and Classes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/unity/unitymanual6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:10:23 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/unity/unitymanual6/</guid>
      <description>Overview - Sounds: This guide will introduce you to Object Oriented Programming and the concept of classes. An AudioManager is used which will enable you to access your sounds library from anywhere in your game.&#xA;To use this guide you will need to download and install Unity and MS Visual Studio. It is recommended that you install the latest versions. Some of the screenshots in this guide have been taken from older versions but should not differ too much.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 7 - Object Orientation Part 2 of 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms7-oop2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:42:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms7-oop2/</guid>
      <description>Overview - Winforms and C# Object Orientation - The Details: To use this guide you will need to download and install MS Visual Studio. It is recommended that you install the latest version. Some of the screenshots in this guide have been taken from older versions but should not differ too much.&#xA;Simply use this guide as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 7 - TileMaps for Fast Game Creation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/unity/unitymanual7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:10:23 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/unity/unitymanual7/</guid>
      <description>Overview - Tilemaps: To use this guide you will need to download and install Unity and MS Visual Studio. It is recommended that you install the latest versions. Some of the screenshots in this guide have been taken from older versions but should not differ too much.&#xA;Simply use this guide as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 8 - Object Orientation Part 3 of 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms8-oop3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:42:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms8-oop3/</guid>
      <description>Overview - Winforms and C# Object Orientation - The Fun Stuff: To use this guide you will need to download and install MS Visual Studio. It is recommended that you install the latest version. Some of the screenshots in this guide have been taken from older versions but should not differ too much.&#xA;Simply use this guide as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 8 - Getting Asset Store Animation to Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/unity/unitymanual8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:10:23 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/unity/unitymanual8/</guid>
      <description>Overview - Working With Asset Store Assets: To use this guide you will need to download and install Unity and MS Visual Studio. It is recommended that you install the latest versions. Some of the screenshots in this guide have been taken from older versions but should not differ too much.&#xA;Simply use this guide as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 9 - Hashing - A Practical Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms9-hashing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:42:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms9-hashing/</guid>
      <description>Overview - Hashing, A Simple Overview: To use this guide you will need to download and install MS Visual Studio. It is recommended that you install the latest version. Some of the screenshots in this guide have been taken from older versions but should not differ too much.&#xA;Simply use this guide as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 10. - String Handling</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms10-stringhandling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 12:42:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms10-stringhandling/</guid>
      <description>Overview - String Handling in C#: To use this guide you will need to download and install MS Visual Studio. It is recommended that you install the latest version. Some of the screenshots in this guide have been taken from older versions but should not differ too much.&#xA;Simply use this guide as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 11 - Access Database and Winforms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms11-dbaccess/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 12:42:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/winforms/winforms11-dbaccess/</guid>
      <description>Overview - Make Your App Work With An Access Database: To use this guide you will need to download and install MS Visual Studio. It is recommended that you install the latest version. Some of the screenshots in this guide have been taken from older versions but should not differ too much.&#xA;Simply use this guide as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A guide to SQL in Access</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/alevel/sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 12:42:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/alevel/sql/</guid>
      <description>Overview: Learn SQL in Access quickly and easily with this guide. It starts off with the basics and goes onto enable you to create some complex queries all within MS-Access.&#xA;Simply use this guide as a self-guided classroom / training room resource. It has been written in MS Word so you can use it as is, or you can edit as appropriate. 1&#xA;CLICK HERE TO DOWNLOAD THE DOCUMENT</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testpage2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/testpage2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 10:28:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/testpage2/</guid>
      <description>This is a test page </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
